SEO YEON (SUNNY) LEE

(702) 498-7457

slee6390@gmail.com

https://github.com/slee6390

Clinical Research Assistant at Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center with emphasis on the values of empathy, communication and creative problem-solving. Main research experience in clinical interviews, data collection and analysis, and MRI brain segmentation. Additional interests in computer science, human-computer interaction, psychology, and education.

EDUCATION

- October 2023
 Introduction to User Experience Design
 Georgia Institute of Technology (Online)
- June 2023 August 2023

 CS50x: Introduction to Computer Science

 HarvardX (Online)
 - August 2018 May 2022

 Bachelor of Science in Neuroscience, Honors

 Bachelor of Arts in Cognitive Science

 University of Southern California (USC)

 Los Angeles, CA
 - Graduated summa cum laude (GPA: 3.94/4.00)Neuroscience Honors Thesis: Differential
 - Neuroscience Honors Thesis: Differential impact of Chd8 haploinsufficiency on social dominance and macrocephaly in two mouse strains
 - USC Dornsife Dean's List (2019 2022)

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- January 2022 May 2022Provost's Research Fellowship
- August 2018 May 2022
 Thematic Option
 Selected for the Thematic Option Honors
 Program, an interdisciplinary core curriculum for 200 out of 3,500 freshmen.
- August 2018 May 2022

 Deans Scholarship
- August 2018 May 2019

 Resident Honors Program (RHP)

 Selected as one of the 20 international students to bypass the senior year and commence studies at the University of Southern California as a freshman.

SKILLS

Clinical research

• Clinical interviews, patient consent forms, study protocols, and IRB submissions

Data collection and analysis

• RedCap, SPSS, Graphpad Prism, AMIRA, BORIS, and Excel

Programming languages

• Working knowledge of C, Python, Javascript, HTML/CSS, SQL, and Git

Languages

• English (bilingual), Korean (bilingual), Spanish (conversational)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

July 2022 - Present

Clinical Research Assistant Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center (BIDMC) | Boston, MA

- Project coordinator of a NIH-funded research project, What the Nose Knows: Hedonic Capacity,
 Psychosocial Interventions and Outcomes in Schizophrenia
- Obtain informed consent from approximately 120 study participants
- Conduct clinical interviews of individuals diagnosed with schizophrenia to gather comprehensive data related to olfaction, negative symptoms, and hedonic capacity
- Organize and manage clinical data to maintain a record of participants of the study, detailing their information and gathered data using RedCap, Excel, and Microsoft Teams
- Draft and submit documents and reports as required by the Institutional Review Board and National Institute of Mental Health
- Train and advise new staff in procedures and protocols

June 2020 - Present

Tutor in SAT, Reading, Grammar, and Mathematics | Online

- Provide one-on-one instructions through online Zoom meetings, developing tailored teaching materials and resources for diverse Korean students, ranging from those in elementary school to adults preparing for the Korean Civil Service Exam
- Enhance test performance up to 300 points for the SAT
- Conduct assessments, monitors academic advancements, and maintains effective communication with both students and parents to provide timely progress updates

January 2019 – May 2022

Research Assistant Levitt Laboratory, Children's Hospital Los Angeles | Los Angeles, CA

- Conducted research under the guidance of Dr. Pat Levitt, focusing on the genetic factors influencing individual variations in social behavior and learning abilities
- Led a project involving the analysis of MRI images of mouse brains to quantify both overall brain volume and specific regions of interest and used the project's findings to compile an Honors Thesis paper highlighting significant genotype-dependent effects influenced by sex and strain, demonstrating how structural brain differences contribute to behavioral variations among strains
- Assessed Direct Social Interaction videos, organized data, conducted graphical and statistical analyses, managed of the mouse colony, and ran behavioral experiments with mice

August 2018 – May 2022

President, Vice President and Events Director

Korean-American Scientists and Engineers Association (KSEA), USC | Los Angeles, CA

- Successfully organized and managed USC events for 30–50 members, overseeing all event details and logistics
- Coordinated invitations and reception for professional speakers at these events, enhancing the overall experience for attendees
- Coordinated Southern California KSEA events serving hundreds of attendees from various sectors, including academia, healthcare, and industry, making a significant impact on the local and regional community

May 2021 - May 2022

Mentor-Mentee Relations Chair WAZO, USC Chapter | Los Angeles, CA

- Initiated and introduced the use of REDCap to establish and manage the mentor-mentee database for this newly founded organization at USC
- Successfully paired around 40 mentors and mentees based on shared identities, personalities, and interests
- Played a key role in the organization's expansion through active recruitment, innovative idea generation, and the establishment of new protocols to enhance overall efficiency
- Provided presentations and organized office hours to assist mentors and mentees in troubleshooting issues as needed

September 2021 – December 2021

Access Aide Office of Student Accessibility Services, USC | Los Angeles, CA

- Provided essential technological assistance to a student with cerebral palsy, ensuring access to course materials and supporting writing assignments
- Adapted classroom content for accessibility, facilitating the student's academic progress
- Coordinated schedules and maintained strict confidentiality regarding all student-related information

PRESENTATIONS

- Schutt, R., Lee, S., Xie, H., Mueser, K., Killam, M., Delman, J., Eack, S., Mesholam-Gately, R.,
 Pratt, S., Sandoval, L., Santos, M., Golden, L., & Keshavan, M. (2023, March 1).

 Cognitive Enhancement Therapy vs Social Skills Training in schizophrenia: a cluster randomized comparative effectiveness evaluation. [Poster Session]. Harvard
 Psychiatry Day and Mysell Lecture, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.
- Lee, S., Tabbaa M., Knoll A., & Levitt P. (2022, January 20 22). Differential impact of Chd8 haploinsufficiency on social dominance and macrocephaly in two mouse strains.

 [Poster Session]. Ygnite KSEA (Korean–American Scientists and Engineers Association), Atlanta, GA, United States.
- Tabbaa M., Knoll A., **Lee, S.**, & Levitt P. (2021, December 13 15). *Integrating genetically diverse mouse reference panels with mutations in an autism risk gene to discover mechanisms regulating social behavioral heterogeneity.* [Conference Session].

 Society for Social Neuroscience conference, online.